[site]: datascience
[post_id]: 97744
[parent_id]: 
[tags]: 
How to choose and create natural language data for machine learning

What the difference between these two data formats? For example, for the Named Entity Recognition task, I learned that index and BIO Encoding are popular data formats to train. Are they have different features for machine learning, and should I choose input data format following training models' requirements? # index representation "entities": [ { "name": "John J. Smith ", "span": [4,8], "type": "PERSON" } # BIO Encoding Tokens IO BIO BMEWO BMEWO+ Yesterday O O O BOS_O afternoon 0 O O O , 0 O O O_PER John I_PER B_PER B_PER B_PER J I_PER I_PER M_PER M_PER . I_PER I_PER M_PER M_PER Smith I_PER I_PER E_PER E_PER traveled O 0 O PER_O to O O O O_LOC Washington I_LOC B_LOC W_LOC W_LOC . O O
